<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joey Carter</title>
    <link>https://joeycarter.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Joey Carter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joeycarter.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dundas Street: Change the Namesake, not the Name</title>
      <link>https://joeycarter.github.io/post/dundas-street/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joeycarter.github.io/post/dundas-street/</guid>
      <description>Every software developer will have at some point in their career been handed a messy, unkempt, monolithic piece of buggy code, strewn with poorly named functions and variables, and they will be tasked with bringing it up to date. There are in fact too tasks here: (a) fix the bugs, i.e. rectify the problems in the software that cause it to behave in an incorrect or unexpected way, and (b) tidy up the code so it looks prettier and easier to understand for the next poor soul who has to deal with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>https://joeycarter.github.io/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joeycarter.github.io/cv/</guid>
      <description>Education Ph.D. in Experimental High Energy Physics · In Progress
University of Toronto, Toronto, ON
B.Sc. Honours Physics (Theory Stream) · 2016
Minor in Biology &amp;amp; Minor in Mathematics
Carleton University, Ottawa, ON
Honours and Awards Edward Christie Stevens Awards In Nuclear Physics · 2017, 2020
University of Toronto · Graduate Fellowship
Cray Inc. Fellowships In Physics · 2018, 2019
University of Toronto · Graduate Fellowship
University of Toronto Fellowship, Faculty of Arts &amp;amp; Science · 2016</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://joeycarter.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joeycarter.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>My primary research interest is the physics of elementary particles at the energy frontier. My research focuses on the ATLAS Experiment, a general-purpose detector at CERN&amp;rsquo;s Large Hadron Collider (LHC) in Geneva, Switzerland, which I joined as an undergraduate in 2015 and continue to work on as a PhD student at the University of Toronto.
Using proton-proton collision data collected by ATLAS during Run-2 of the LHC, my data analysis activities have focused on Higgs boson physics and searches for physics beyond the Standard Model in the Higgs sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconciling My Cognitive Dissonance</title>
      <link>https://joeycarter.github.io/post/reconciling-my-cognitive-dissonance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joeycarter.github.io/post/reconciling-my-cognitive-dissonance/</guid>
      <description>This essay originally appeared on my Medium Blog.
 Grad school is rough.
I had no illusions that it would be any other way when I signed away the next five years of my life to the University of Toronto last spring to study particle physics. I knew it would be hard work. I knew that I would regularly be burning the midnight oil to finish assignments, scrambling to make plots for a presentation the next morning, fighting with LaTeX to format that godforsaken bibliography in the style ordained by the council of physics elders eons ago, and all the other grunt work that goes along with a life in academia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take a Science Course</title>
      <link>https://joeycarter.github.io/post/take-a-science-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joeycarter.github.io/post/take-a-science-course/</guid>
      <description>Update | September 25, 2017
This essay was originally published on Carleton&amp;rsquo;s Learning Log three years ago to this day. I wanted to revisit it to give it some long-overdue polishing and clarification.
 There has always been a subtle tension between the students studying science, technology and mathematics and those studying the arts. This slight friction seems to begin around the time that students fresh out of high school enter university and old friends you have seen every day in class for the past four years all of sudden have an entirely different schedule from yours, and the discussions begin on how the subject you are studying is superior to everyone else&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>